albawaba.com 2010-11-29

# 

Privacy & Disclaimer Policy

 ** _Using the Al Bawaba Network\"s Services_**

**The following statement explains Al Bawaba\"s policy regarding the personal information we collect about you.**

## **1. Introduction**

This policy covers Al Bawaba\"s use of personal information that the Al Bawaba collects when you use albawaba.com and/or menareport.com.

From time to time, you will be asked to submit personal information about yourself (e.g. name and email address) in order to receive or use services on our website. Such services include ecards, forums, newsletters, competitions, blogging, downloads of music and other content.

By entering your details in the fields requested, you enable Al Bawaba and its service providers to provide you with the services you select. Whenever you provide such personal information, we will treat that information in accordance with this policy. When using your personal information Al Bawaba will act in accordance with current legislation and aim to meet current Internet best practice.

## **2.  Visitor Information**

During the course of any visit to albawaba.com and/or menareport.com, the pages you see, along with a short text file called a \'cookie\', are downloaded to your computer. Many websites do this, because cookies enable website publishers to do useful things like find out whether the computer (and probably its user) has visited the website before. This is done on a repeat visit by checking to see, and finding, the cookie left there on the last visit.

Information supplied by cookies can help us to provide you with a better online user experience and assist us to analyse the profile of our visitors. For example: if on a previous visit you went to our education pages, we might find this out from your cookie and highlight educational information on your second and subsequent visits.

## **3.  What is a cookie?**

A cookie is a small amount of data, which often includes an anonymous unique identifier that is sent to your browser from a website\'s computer and stored on your computer\'s hard drive. Each website can send its own cookie to your browser if your browser\'s preferences allow it, but (to protect your privacy) your browser only permits a web site to access the cookies it has already sent to you, not the cookies sent to you by other sites.

Many sites do this whenever a user visits their website in order to track online traffic flows.

Cookies record information about your online preferences. Users have the opportunity to set their computers to accept all cookies, to notify them when a cookie is issued, or not to receive cookies at any time. The last of these, of course, means that certain personalised services cannot then be provided to that user user and accordingly you may not be able to take full advantage of all of the bbc.co.uk features. Each browser is different, so check the \"Help\" menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences.

If you have set your computer to reject cookies you can still browse albawaba.com and/or menareport.com anonymously until such time as you wish to register for Al Bawaba\"s services. For further information on cookies please visit _www.aboutcookies.org_.

## **4.  Use and storage of your personal information**

When you supply any personal information to Al Bawaba we have legal obligations towards you in the way we use that data. We must collect the information fairly, that is, we must explain how we will use it and tell you if we want to pass the information on to anyone else.

In general, any information you provide to the Al Bawaba will only be used within Al Bawaba and by its agents and service providers. Your information will be disclosed where we are obliged or permitted by law. Also, if you post or send offensive, inappropriate or objectionable content anywhere on albawaba.com and/or menareport.com or to Al Bawaba or otherwise engage in any disruptive behaviour on albawaba.com and/or menareport.com, Al Bawaba can use whatever information that is available to it about you to stop such behaviour. This may involve informing relevant third parties such as your employer, school e-mail/Internet provider and law enforcement agencies about the content and your behaviour.

We will hold your personal information on our systems for as long as you use the service you have requested, and remove it in the event that the purpose has been met. For safety reasons, however, Al Bawaba may store messaging transcript data (including message content, member names, times and dates) arising from the use of albawaba.com and/or menareport.com community services for a period of six months. Where personal information is held for people who are not yet registered but have taken part in other albawaba.com and/or menareport.com services (e.g. competitions), that information will be held as long as is necessary to ensure that the service is run smoothly. We will ensure that all personal information supplied is held securely, in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998.

If you are notified on an albawaba.com and/or menareport.com site that your information may be used to allow Al bawaba to contact you, this means that Al Bawaba may contact you for a number of purposes. For example, we may wish to provide you with password reminders or notify you that the particular service has been suspended for maintenance.

## **5.  Users 16 and under**

If you are aged 16 or under, please get your parent/guardian\'s permission beforehand whenever you provide personal information to albawaba.com and/or menareport.com. Users without this consent are not allowed to provide us with personal information.

**6.  Trademarks**

Al Bawaba, MenaReport, \'Gateway To The Middle East\', \'News You Can Use\' and Middle East and North Africa Business Report\' and the Al Bawaba and MenaReport logos are trademarks of Albawaba.com, Inc.. All other trademarks and/or brands represented on the Al Bawaba Network are trademarks or registered trademarks of their respective companies or owners.

If you would like to know more and/or need an clarifications about the Al Bawaba Network\"s Privacy Policy and/or Disclaimer, please feel free to contact _webmaster@albawaba.com_.

If you would like to make commercial use of any of the Al Bawaba Network\"s content and/or services, please contact _sales@albawaba.com_ for more information.
